<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page theme="default">
    <title>nsafran.com - This Website's Design</title>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <window-title>Terminal - This Website's Design</window-title>
            <content>
<h1>This Website's Design</h1>

<p><em>Published: 22-May-2025 - Last Updated: 22-May-2025</em></p>

<p>When I originally made a website, I used Publii, which is a WSYIWYG static site generator. Publii worked good, but I wanted a bit more control over the layout and organization of the site.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.cosam.org/">cosam.org</a> was my inspiration for the layout of the site, with a sidebar that changed depending on the page. <br />
<a href="https://www.4dwm.com/">4dwm.com</a> inspired me to make the site look like a CDE/HP VUE/4DWM desktop. </p>

<p>This ended up being a lot of work since I have no experience with web design, except for one class I took in 10th grade making websites in Adobe Dreamweaver CS3 (which was very outdated by then).
Orignally, it was going to look much closer to cosam.org with a simpler theme. I was planning on using <a href="https://simplecss.org/">https://simplecss.org/</a> for the styling, but ended up just making my own.  </p>

<p>I had a few goals for the site: Make it static, so I can host it on GitHub Pages, no Javascript so older browsers can at least load the site, and for it to be somewhat easy to update with new content.
<a href="https://github.com/nsafran1217/cde-website">GitHub for the website "source"</a></p>

<p>The first draft of the site was all HTML with a small amount of Javascript to load the navbar on each page, but that didn't meet my goal for no JS. I then came across xslt, which allows you to use a template file to convert an XML file into an HTML file.</p>

<p>With some help from ChatGPT, I started tweaking the template to insert the navbar template on each site. The xslt template also let me generate multiple "Windows" on the site relatively easily. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>